Alma Lisboa

Operations Manager

Willingboro, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Alma-Lisboa/9be555238f7040e4

Operations, Logistics, Sales Support Professional with extensive experience in Customer Service, Order and Allocation Management, and shipping for manufacturers of retail products. Background also includes staff supervision. Proficiency in creating tools and templates using computer software. Fluent in Spanish. Areas of expertise:

- Customer Service Inventory SAP & Blue Cherry
- Order Management Reports EDI
- Operations / Logistics Staff Supervision Microsoft Office
- Allocation Vendor Compliance
- · Shipping · Invoicing

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Manager

Fashion Accessory Bazaar - New York, NY - 2012 to 2014

Supervised staff of 10 consisting of Allocations, Order entry, Billing, EDI, Receiving, California warehouse personnel.

- · Monitor Blue Cherry system allocation process, create pick tickets, ensure routing requests are performed
- Review open order reports daily to ensure timely shipping to customers.
- Review Planning and Shipping strategies by customers' requirements.
- Perform finished goods receiving functions, resolving any discrepancies between the quantities on the PO and Quantities Received.
- Generate and monitor an accurate daily shipping report/forecast.
- Research and resolve all customer quality issues, return authorizations, operational chargeback's and serve as liaison between sales, finance, production and credit department.
- Assist in annual physical inventory process and reconciliation. Review charges on all invoices from warehouse and domestic trucking companies and approve for processing.
- Monitor research and resolve inventory discrepancies between Blue Cherry system and warehouse.
- Review all routing guides for all new accounts and review findings with the allocation team.
- Monitor the quality, quantity, cost and efficiency of the movement and storage of goods.
- Analyzing data to monitor performance and plan improvements and demand
- Liaising and negotiating with customers and suppliers
- Resolved logistical problems and producing new solutions
- Manage allocations to support sales forecast, communicate issues with sales.
- Travel to California to review warehouse policies and procedures with FAB personnel and third party warehouse owners.

Allocation Manager for Sean John and Ellen Tracy

LF USA - New York, NY - 2010 to 2012

Revised delivery dates, prices, store distributions, and shipping terms as written by sales associates.

• Handled Replenishment Analysis to ensure product was readily available. Processed and reviewed all EDI transactions for accuracy and changes.

- Handled Shipping date discrepancies, anticipated delays and any additional information pertaining to warehouse shipments. Worked with Production and Logistics Departments to ensure timely shipments on product and informed of any delays.
- Responsible for all allocation/ticketing, and re-ticketing of goods to the warehouse.
- Coordinated with Warehouse and Traffic Departments on routing guidelines and shipments.
- Managed RA's/customer problems with accounts and short shipments.
- Prepared daily reports to inform sales of shipping, bookings, and MTD sales.
- Responsible for inventory accuracy and quality results.
- Worked in conjunction with Production department to track and ensure finished goods deliveries were on schedule to meet company's demand.
- Provided reliable and accurate information to finance to meet end of month closing schedules.
- Identified and implemented processes to reduce customer charge backs.
- Communicated shipping delays and out of stock situations to appropriate department and teams.
- Managed SAP EDI cockpit and processed stuck orders due to UPC/SKU cross-reference and setup.

Customer Service Manager and Retail Planner Coordinator

SEAN JOHN - Cranbury, NJ - 2006 to 2010

Managed six Customer Service representatives and supervised order entry process.

- Created reports in Blue Cherry for Managers and Executives.
- Managed cancellations, oversold, bulk order confirmations and inventory figures on the management report. Reduced oversold to 2 percent or less per season.
- Reviewed EDI transmissions on a daily basis and worked on any discrepancies.
- Maintained Customer Master Data base. Managed Outlet and Sean John stores accounts.
- Organized and shipped samples for the sales forces pre-market.
- Inactivated styles with poor bookings and notified sales team.
- Managed Employee allowance program, budget quarterly and Mr. Combs' personal product account.
- Served as international account coordinator / liaison.
- Managed Commission Statements for road representatives.
- Supervised Returns and Refusals policies and procedures.
- Provided weekly ad hoc reporting to senior management recapping bookings, shipping, and retail sales results.
- Executed merchandise wholesale purchasing starting with Holiday 2010 season.
- Managed seasonal line lists.

Logistics and Operations Coordinator

SWATCH GROUP USA - 2002 to 2006

Managed receipt and distribution of product for three Luxury watch brands.

- Consolidated inventory for all three brands once a month.
- Developed, analyzed, and submitted inventory to the factory.
- Analyzed delivery and production schedule while staying on top of factory to ensure goods were received as confirmed.
- Coordinated and tracked time-sensitive/urgent deliveries with import department to ensure speedy customs process.
- Approved all documentation and logistics of incoming watch orders before shipping from the factories.
- Received all invoices and communicated incoming product to sales force and vendors.
- Prepared all Export documentation.
- Analyzed value of orders to determine method of shipping.
- Allocated incoming watches to accounts.

• Coordinated and executed stock transfers, created invoices for all sales, maintained inventory of watches, pens and jewelry and tracked all repairs for Breguet Madison Avenue Boutique.

SWATCH GROUP USA - Weehawken, NJ - 1998 to 2006

Sales and Operations Coordinator

SWATCH GROUP USA - 2000 to 2002

Tracked and submitted weekly sales figures.

- Updated retailers contact lists and accounts.
- Tracked all new account submissions and follow-up with credit department to ensure timely delivery.
- · Supported sales, return authorization, sample line returns, sales invoices, and purchase order entry.
- Supported Brand Managers on budgets, forecasts, sales analysis, and product allocation.
- Prepared reports on regular basis including sales, product availability, open order, and backorder.
- Produced month to date sales reports and monthly sales flash.

Customer Service Supervisor

SWATCH GROUP USA - 1998 to 2000

Managed training and management program for customer service representatives. Train in the transition from AS400 to SAP.

- Ensured accuracy of orders for five brands, guaranteed same day allocation of said orders, and coordinate with warehouse to maintain delivery turnover rate. Troubleshoot client difficulties.
- Handled multiple corporate accounts by telephone, mail, and e-mail. Verified credit.
- Supervised and worked with sales coordinators for all brands.
- Prepared and distributed daily Electronic Data Intermission reports.
- Placed all production orders with vendors.

EDUCATION

St. Peter's College - Jersey City, NJ